[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：所以我要开始练习5和
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So I'm going to open exercise 5 and
然后我要分裂我的观点。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：以及
then I'm going to split my view. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: And
我要打开固定在侧面的练习3
I'm going to open exercise 3 fixed on the side so
我们可以比较这两个，实际上是相反的。
that we can compare these two, actually do that reverse.
所以我们要试着做一个并排的比较
So we're going to try to do a side by side comparison of what we were
我们是如何解决承诺的，我们将如何解决异步问题
how we were solving Promises with how we're gonna solve it with asynquence
因为练习的目的是向你展示相似性和
because the purpose of the exercise that is to show you the similarities and
炫耀一下异步是如何改善的。
show off a little bit of how asynquence can improve.
好的，首先我们有getFile函数。
Okay, so first of all we have the getFile function.
在左边，你可以看到我们正在创造一个承诺。
And on the left you can see that we're creating a Promise.
所以在右边，我们想做一些非常类似的事情，但只是一个步骤序列
So on the right we want to do something very similar but a single step sequence
和承诺是一样的，在概念上大致是一样的。
is the same thing as a Promise, roughly conceptually the same thing.
所以要创建一个单步异步，我们将调用ASQ，
So to create a single step asynquence, we're gonna make call ASQ,
函数ASQ，它接收我们需要调用的回调
the function ASQ, which receives a callback that we need to call so
这很像我们在这里获得的Resolve回调。
that's much like the resolve callback that we're getting over here.
让我稍微缩小一下
Let me zoom out just slightly so
一次看到更多更容易，好吗？
it's a little easier to see more at a time, okay?
我们仍然要调用虚假的Ajax调用。
And we're still going to call the fake Ajax call.
有了文件URL，我们将传入Done而不是Resolve。
With the file URL in we're gonna pass in done instead of resolve.
所以这就是我们要做的所有事情，使一个步骤不同步
So that's all we have to do to make a single step asynquence
呼叫，以最传统的方式。
call, in the most traditional way possible.
你会注意到这和承诺基本上是一样的
And you'll notice that it's basically the same thing as the Promise
只是它更短更简单。
except it's a little shorter and simpler.
我们不会调用新关键字。
We're not calling the new keyword.
我们没有更复杂的解决方案
We don't have some more complicated set of resolve and
拒绝，我们必须保持跟踪，我们只有一个单一的回调完成。
reject that we're having to keep track of, we just have the single callback for done.
有一些方法可以发出错误信号，但您没有单独的回调。
There are ways to signal errors, but you don't have a separate callback for that.
所以我们会深入到这一点，但我只想快速地向你们展示这一点
So well get too far into that, but I do just want to quickly show you that
拥有图书馆的价值在于我们可以
the value of having a library is that there are additional benefits that we can
这些好处之一就是需要包装是一种非常常见的模式
get so one of those benefits is that it's such a common pattern to need to wrap
喜欢创建这些包装的实用程序。
like to create these wrapped utilities.
基本上，它被称为提升，取一个只接收回调和
Basically it's called lifting taking a function that only receives callbacks and
将其转化为一个函数，它将返回我们的异步或
turning that into a function that will return us asynquence or
作为承诺回报。
return as a Promise.
所以做同样事情的另一种方法是
So another way of doing that same thing would have been
让我自己成为一个getFile。
to to make myself a getFile.
并调用库中存在的ASQ.rap实用程序。
And calling an ASQ.wrap utility that exists in the library.
它的工作是接受一个回调期望函数
Its job is to take a callback expecting function and
使其成为一个承诺期望或承诺返回函数。
make it into a Promise expecting or Promise returning function.
因此，如果我们将fakeAjax传递给它。
So if we pass in fakeAjax to it.
默认情况下，这里的假设是它将回调视为
Now by default the assumption here is that it treats callbacks as
错误优先样式，因为这在节点世界中非常常见。
error first style, because that's extremely common in the node world.
在我们特定情况下，fakeAjax不是样式错误。
In our particular case fakeAjax is not error for style.
所以我们不想做这个假设。
So we don't wanna make that assumption.
但在大多数情况下，您将处理错误
But in the most majority case you're gonna be dealing with error
第一个瓦片功能遍及节点或其他角库或
first tile functions all over node or other Angular libraries or
无论在哪种情况下，您只需调用WRAP就行了。
whatever in which case, you just call wrap and that's it.
现在我们有了getFile函数，我不需要做任何其他事情。
And now we have a getFile function, I didn't need to do anything else.
我现在有了getFile函数，它将以异步方式返回我们，这就完成了。
I now have the getFile function that will return us in asynquence and that's done.
您可以将此包装配置为执行其他操作，在这种情况下，
You can configure this wrap to do other things, and in this case,
我们要告诉它我们想做一个简单的风格
we're going to tell it that we want to do a simplecb style
包装，因为我们假设fakeAjax函数
wrapping because we're assuming that the fakeAjax function
我们正在处理的是一个简单的回调，而不是错误优先的样式。
that we're dealing with is a simple callback rather than error first style so.
有关如何配置WRAP的文档。
Documentation on how you can configure wrap a little bit.
大多数时候你根本不需要做任何配置，但它有选项
Most of the time you won't need to do any configuration at all but it has the option
改变你需要的包装行为，但是第22行
of changing that wrapping behavior you need but that one line there on line 22
这就是我创建包装的getFile函数所需要做的全部工作。
that's all I need to do to create my wrapped getFile function.
并且我可以完全相同的方式调用getFile
And I can call getFile exactly the same way
正如我所期望的那样。
as I would expect to be able to call it so.
我只是想炫耀一下有一些这样的东西
I just wanted to show off that there are what there are some of those sorts of
他们可以在其上添加这些实用程序的异步库的好处，
benefits from from asynchronous libraries they can add these utilities on,
在正常课程的基础上，帮助制作一些这样的东西
on top of the normal course stuff and help make some of these
我们所做的任务，这些补救性任务更直截了当。
tasks that we do, these remedial tasks a little bit more straight forward.
好的，所以我们只用比较容易理解的，但是
Okay, so we'll just stick with the easier to understand one but
你可以知道有些东西像包装。
you can know that there are things like wrapping.
好吧，那马上要求文件怎么样？
All right, what about requesting the files at once?
我将把我的s1称为s1，因为它是一个序列而不是p1，但是
Well I'm gonna call mine s1 cuz it's a sequence instead of p1 but
基本上仍然是对file1的getFile调用。
is still fundamentally gonna be a getFile call with file1.
S2是getFile(“File2”)和
And s2 is getFile("file2") and
S3是getFile(“file3”)，好吗？
s3 is getFile("file3"), okay?
好的，这很简单。
All right, so that's pretty straightforward.
让我们去链条上
Let's go to the chain and
看看链条工作方式的不同。
look at the difference in the in the way the chains gonna work.
我们有一个S1，它代表我们前进的链条上的第一步
We have an s1 that represents the first step in our chains us going
和p1一样。
to the same thing as p1.
现在异步API中，而不是调用一个.Then
Now in the asynquence API, rather than calling a .then
每当我们想要做一些异步步骤。
whenever we want to do some asynchronous step.
如果我们有异步步骤，这就是输出，我们使用.val。
If we have asynchronous step, which is what output is, we use .val.
所以我要打电话给.val，然后
So I'm going to call .val, and
传递输出。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：记住这是为了
pass an output. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Remember this is to get
除了可能使API更难学习的多态性之外，
away from the polymorphism that can make APIs harder to learn instead,
你只需要学习每一步，很明显Val是一个同步的步骤，
you just learn each step, and it's clear that val is a synchronous step,
与异步步骤相反。
as opposed to an asynchronous step.
好的，那么下一个，我需要在p2步骤中链接，对吗？
All right, so the next one, I need to to link in the p2 step, right?
现在，记住，我告诉过你我们有.seq用于接收序列。
Now, remember, I told you that we have .seq for receiving sequences.
所以我们可以做.seq和
So we could do .seq and
返回S2。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：长相
return s2. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Looks
与我们处理允诺链的方式非常相似。
very similar to the way that we do with Promise chain.
拥有Promise库的好处之一
One of the advantages of having a Promise library to give you
额外的抽象，以消除一些这些纸张切割和其他无意义的开销。
extra abstractions to remove some of these paper cuts and other pointless overheads.
Asynquence允许您直接通过S2。
Asynquence allows you to just pass s2 directly.
我很乐意和承诺链一起拥有它。
I'd love to have that with the Promise chains.
我们没有这个，但是有了一个序列，我们就可以直接传递S2，然后
We don't have that but with a sequence we can just pass s2 directly and
然后我们执行.val(输出)。
so then we do .val(output).
然后我们执行.seq(S3)。
Then we do .seq(s3).
然后我们执行.val(输出)。
Then we do .val(output).
然后我们执行.val，output(“Ccomplete！”)，
Then we do .val, output("Ccomplete!"),
好吗？&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：in
okay? &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: In
除了观察之外，
addition to making that observation,
如果我知道我可以将这些序列直接传递到这些步骤中，
if I know that I can pass these sequences directly into those steps,
这实际上意味着，我甚至不需要将这些存储在单独的变量中。
what that actually means is I don't even need to store these in separate variables.
我可以从字面上接受getFile调用，替换S1。
I can literally take the getFile call, replace s1.
我可以接受这个getFile调用，并将其放在S2的位置上。
I can take this getFile call and put it right in place of s2.
我可以调用这个getFile调用
And I can call this getFile call and
将其放在S3的正确位置。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：Get
put it right in place of s3. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Get
把这些全扔掉。
rid of those entirely.
它仍然在进行所有三个getFile调用。
It's still making all three getFile calls.
一个在29线，一个在31线，一个在33线，
The one on line 29, one on line 31, and the one on line 33,
它仍然在预先做这些，所有这些都是一次性的，因为它们仍然是函数调用。
it's still making those all upfront, all at once cuz they're still function calls.
但这些返回值立即通过管道传输到链中，并且
But those return values are immediately piped into a chain, and
链知道如何处理它并将其排序为正确的顺序。
the chain knows how to handle that and sequence it into the proper order.
所以我甚至不需要将它们存储在单独的变量中
So I don't even have to store them in separate variables and
创建一个函数来返回它们，所以我只是让它简单明了。
make a function to return them, so I just have it straightforward.
所以这是试图说明我提出的一个观点，就是
So this is trying to illustrate one of the points that I'm making, is that
承诺图书馆的价值，不管你喜欢不喜欢我的，我都没有利害关系
the value of a Promise library, whether you like mine or not, I have no stake in
不管你喜欢这个特别的，但是有一大堆很棒的。
whether you like this particular one, but there's a bunch of great ones out there.
Promise库的目的是使用Promises更容易，并且
The purpose of Promise libraries is to make it easier to work with Promises, and
我希望你能看到我们在右边所做的是
I hope that you can see that what we did on the right hand side Is
比起我们在左手边做同样的事情要容易得多。
quite a bit easier than what we had to do the same equivalent on the left-hand side.
这是试图使用承诺抽象的优点，
That's the virtue of trying to use Promise abstractions,
就是他们可以自由地去掉一些丑陋的部分，粗糙的边缘，
is that they have the freedom to get rid of some of the ugly bits, the rough edges,
那个奇怪的角落案子。
the weird corner case.
他们有能力铺设一些这样的东西，而且
They have the ability to kind of pave over some of those things, and
这是背后的设计哲学的一部分
that's part of the design philosophy behind
异步，好吗？&gt；&gt；扬声器2：我当时用了而不是
asynquence, okay? &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I used then instead of
序列，有什么区别？&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：那么
sequence, what's the difference? &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: The .then
函数将调用它接收的函数，如果它接收到一个函数。
function will call it the function that it receives and if it receives a function.
它将调用它接收的函数，并向它传递一个完成回调。
It will call the function that it receives and pass it a done call back.
的.Then关键字
The .then keyword for
遗留原因在以下意义上是多态的
legacy reasons is polymorphic in the sense that
如果您不正确地使用它并传递给它一个序列，它就不会在您面前哽咽。
if you use it incorrectly and pass it a sequence, it will not choke at you.
但是正确的习惯用法是为正确的事情调用适当的步骤。
But the proper idiomatic usage is to call the proper step for the proper thing.
所以，这一步的目的就是当你想把事情做完的时候
So the purpose of the .then step is when you want to get the done
函数作为延续，您可以根据需要使用该延续。
function as a continuation and you can use that continuation however you need.
序列步骤的目的是要创建自己的序列
The purpose of the sequence step is that you are going to make your own sequence
然后把它放回链子里。
and return it into the chain.
这说得通吗？
That makes sense?
用我的API进行5到10分钟的练习，你就会有这样的感觉，
And with five or ten minutes of practice with my API you'll get the sense of,
我用这一步来达到这个目的，这一步就是为了达到那个目的。
I use this step for that purpose this step for that purpose.
这就是目标。
That's the goal.